I'm here with the newest Carolina
Panther Monroe Freeling first round pick
out of the University of Georgia. For
starters, you hear your name called,
describe [clears throat] that moment. I
mean the phone call was kind of funny. I
I think I said I love you. I did not I
wasn't thinking I feel like I was so
surreal and I actually ran out of tears.
I was just talking to me about it, but
yeah, hear my name called especially
just in my home state almost it's like
it was surreal. I mean it was awesome.
Like just thinking like wow like I'm not
picking up and going across the country.
I'm just going down the road. So it was
awesome. When you have a moment like
that often you kind of go back in time
and you think of what got you to that
point. What was the first moment that
you thought of as a flashback?
I mean really just the fact that like I
was playing
how for how long I've been playing
football and everything that took and
especially like this last year I felt
like was so like tough especially coming
off of such a
tough game. I went to lay him surgery
and then I was just kind of out and the
whole spring and I didn't really get to
do much and so the fact that I came all
this way and and I'm at this point I'm
now I'm a professional football player
as what I wanted to be as a young and
was it's just insane. It really is
surreal.
Charleston area kid.
What connection if any did you have to
the Carolina Panthers growing up? You
know I didn't I don't really have any
allegiance cuz I ended up I moved there
when I was like 10 years old or not 10
but 12 or something.
But there was a lot of you know Carolina
fans around me and you know funny thing
is that I think that a lot of the fan
bases especially Clemson and South
Carolina were mad at me for going out of
state. So I hope I can repay them now
that I'm here. They love me now. They
love me now.
>> here in Carolina. So
yeah, no it's really good thing but I
didn't really have
true allegiance to any team especially
as growing up.
>> One of the things we've heard in the
last 24 hours is what a great athlete
you are.
Where do you get the athleticism from
mom or dad? My mom. Definitely my mom.
My dad's not going to like to hear that
but definitely my mom. What kind of
athlete was mom?
She played basketball, she played
volleyball
in high school and then she's kind of a
triathlete and now she's done yoga for
almost 10 years now and I get that from
her too.
Your dad does have an athletic past too.
Tell us about that. Yeah, so he
didn't play a single snap of American
football but he played rugby whenever he
was growing up and you know weird thing
about dads is that you really don't get
to hear a lot about their past until
just some random night on a random
Tuesday. So I don't know if I'm going to
find out more about his past and how
good he was at rugby but he played
yeah that in South Africa. So Let's go
back to mom and yoga because yoga's had
an impact on your life growing up. How
did you get introduced to yoga? Yeah, so
my freshman year of high school was
COVID happened which is crazy
if you think about it but yeah COVID
happened and there wasn't really much
going on and so my mom was like hey you
want to start doing yoga and we actually
just got a weights in my garage. So I
was really starting to like lift and
like get bigger and
so we just started doing yoga my mom was
like you want to do yoga? So we invited
some of the some of the other offensive
lineman over that were on my team and we
just started doing yoga in our garage
and it kind of built from that and I
started and there was so many like
benefits to it like I wasn't as sore and
I was you know able to lift more and
there was just so many benefits that I
noticed and I just kind of kept it going
and here I am now and it's still with me
and I think it's
I credit it to a lot of my
athleticism I think.
Is the breathing aspect
something that you've used as well
whether it's in a big moment that that
breathiness they teach you? No
definitely. I think that also like
whenever I did get injured in 24 or 25
the whole off season I ended up starting
meditating before games and so
I don't know if that came with it but I
do know that like there was sometimes I
think I gave up a sack this last year
against Tennessee and I was like now I'm
just going to come back to my breath
like that's what yoga's all about and
you know being in those
compromising positions especially like
whenever you're tired or whatever but no
it definitely makes a difference. You
had a brother who played basketball at
Queens right here in Charlotte. What has
he told you about
your new hometown or your new town? I
mean he's going to have to tell me more
but I came and visited him like a couple
times I think but I mean for the most
part I think he was kind of locked in on
campus. I'll have to find out whatever
he said and what he has to say about
Charlotte but I mean I know it's a great
city. I mean I'm it's again it's insane
that I'm actually here. I'm really here
in Charlotte. It feels like it was meant
to be just my brother was here like the
high school coaches here like everyone's
here. So
You go to Georgia
and a lot's been made that you only
started 18 games but I look at Georgia's
defense and all the guys that they
turned out that are playing in the NFL.
What did that do for you in practice
facing future pros every day? I mean it
gave me confidence number one in my
decision to come out which has paid off
as we can see but really just the fact
that I was be able to go against so many
NFL guys made me a better football
player and like people say only 18
starts but yeah I have like a thousand
starts against these NFL players that
are playing in the league right now. So
it's like it's it definitely helped me
with my career. What else was it about
Georgia and playing in the SEC that you
feel prepared you for the NFL? I mean I
don't know if you've been to any of our
practices but they're brutal.
So from everyone's feedback from any NFL
team from players that have left Georgia
say it's 10 times easier. So that's
definitely something that I like now I
wouldn't say I'm looking forward to the
practice being easier but definitely a
little less on my body but also just
like the attention to detail we have at
Georgia I think is really been the
culture we have. So coming to a place
that has such a strong fan base and such
a culture like I see the
core traits they have all over the walls
here. I'm really excited to come to a
place that has such a strong culture cuz
I think that is really what makes or
breaks teams and especially the keep
pounding go to the fourth quarter. We
had something similar called keep
chopping. So you know the tree is going
to go down eventually. So that's how I
feel.
Going to carry it over here. And you're
familiar with being in a pressure
cooker. You go to Georgia expectation
there was to win.
You step into a place now they're coming
off a playoff run.
That shouldn't be anything new, right? I
want to win.
You draft a winner I'm going to try to
be a winner. Well let's end on this.
You're an offensive lineman. Who were
some of the guys that you admired
growing up who played your position? You
know I grew up you know I was half my
life I spent in Bend Oregon and so I was
an Oregon fan. So Penei Sewell actually
coming out of college you know he had a
highlight tape and I was like wow that's
awesome. That's really awesome. So
really him in the run game and then
Andrew Thomas uh
uh from Georgia he was you know I really
like his sets you know I think I want to
put that into my game too. So there's
definitely a whole lot of offensive
lineman that I'm trying to you know
incorporate into my game but at the end
of the day I want to be my own player.
So Monroe Freeling welcome to Charlotte.
Welcome to the Panthers. Yes sir. Thank
you.
>> [music]
[music]